Guide to the Church League of America Collection of the Research Files of Counterattack, the Wackenhut Corporation, and Karl Baarslag TAM.148
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Counterattack Research Files, 1928-1967
  - Subseries I: Countries, 1938-1958
    - Greece (10-32) [Includes Matrerials Prepared by the US Department of State], 1944-1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Canada (10-46), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - India (10-60), 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Hawaiian Islands (10-90) [Includes Pamphlet, "The Truth About Communism in Hawaii," by Ichiro Izuko], 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subseries II: Communist Party of the United States of America, 1938-1961
    This subseries contains the research files of Counterattack on the Communist Party USA (CPUSA), the bulk of which were collected in the 1940s. ABC was interested in monitoring and understanding the operating procedures the CPUSA, its members, and other organizations they were involved in. ABC used their research to identify Communists in entertainment, business, and unions and implicate individuals and organizations in their publication. The research files consist of clippings, reports, flyers, pamphlets, circulars, internal correspondence, member lists, and other materials collected by Counterattack. Counterattack organized their files by district of the CPUSA and then by subject. Each file contains collected information on districts and groups within the CPUSA. The bulk of the material is New York based. Most districts of the CPUSA are underrepresented or are completely unrepresented in Counterattack's files. District files contain information pertaining to members and activities of the districts. Subject files are divided into cultural and educational activities, organizational policy, minority groups, youth, veterans, and organizational and tactical activities of the CPUSA. The series also contains CPUSA conference proceedings, articles, and other information on the Smith Act trials in 1949.
    - Communist Party File System, Classification 11 (11-0), Jul 11, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Leaders, Officials, Individuals [Smith Act] (11-0), 1939, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Proceedings of Eastern Seabord Conference of Communist Party held at Webster Hall (11-0-A), Oct 1947 (Box 2, Folder 27-28)
    - Communist Party USA (11-1), 1939-1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Trial of the "11" (11-1A), 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Trial of the "11" (11-1A), 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - District 1, Maine, Massachusetts, Vermont, New Hampshire, and Rhode Island (11-2), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - District 2, New York (11-3), 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - Bronx, New York (11-3A), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn, New York (11-3B), 1945-1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Manhattan, New York (11-3C), 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Queens, New York (11-3D), 1936-1946 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
    - Upstate New York (11-3E), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - District 4, Washington, DC and Maryland (11-5), 1946-1953 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - District 6, Ohio (11-7), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - District 7, Michigan (11-8), 1940-1948 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - District 8, Illinois, Indiana, and Kentucky (11-9), 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - District 9, Minnesota, North Dakota, and South Dakota (11-10), 1940-1961 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - District 12, Washington, Oregon, and Idaho (11-11), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - District 13, California, Arizona, and Nevada (11-12), 1940-1951 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
    - District 14, New Jersey (11-13), 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - District 18, Wisconsin (11-15), 1940-1946 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - District 23, Texas (11-19), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - District 24, Louisiana (11-20), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - District 26, Virginia, North Carolina, and South Carolina (11-22), 1947 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - District 27, Alabama, Georgia, Mississippi, and Tennessee (11-23), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - District 28, Arkansas and Oklahoma (11-24), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - District 32-35, Nebraska, Iowa, Kansas, and Utah (11-26), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Communist Party International (11-27), 1939, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Comintern (11-27A), 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Cultural (11-28), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Federal Government (11-29), 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Ideology (11-30), 1938-1939, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Jews (11-31), 1946-1953 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Negroes (11-32), 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Professional (11-33), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Publications (11-34), 1940-1947 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Daily Worker (11-34A), 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Daily Worker [Daily Worker Subscribers] (11-34A), undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Daily Worker [Index of Photographs] (11-34A), 1942 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Daily Worker Abstracts (11-34A), Jan 1, 1935-Jun 23, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Tactics (11-35), 1938-1948 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Youth (11-36), 1940-1952 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Veterans (11-37), 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Education (11-38), 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Organization (11-39), 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Trade Unions (11-40), 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - New York State Elections (11-41), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Religion (11-42), 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Communist Activities in South (11-43), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Radio (11-44), 1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Party Lines (11-45), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Food Industry (11-46), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - New York State Convention Proceedings (11-47), Jul 1948 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Communist Party USA National Convention (11-48), Aug 1948 (Box 4, Folder 12-16)
    - Laws and Bills Affecting the Communist Party USA (11-49), 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Subseries III: Communist Party USA Front Organizations, 1934-1966
    This subseries contains mostly research files of Counterattack on organizations that Counterattack viewed as possible Communist Party fronts, the bulk of which were collected in the 1940s. Much of the activity of the Communist Party took place in the context of working within mass organizations; those established by the Party were often referred to as front organizations. Mass organizations were usually devoted to a single issue or constituency and had a broader membership and political appeal than that of the official Party line. Some organizations within this series were known fronts, others were suspected fronts by ABC. The materials in this subseries afford a perspective of both anti-Communist efforts to expose front organizations as well as the leftist political agenda of these alleged fronts in terms of postwar domestic and foreign policy.
    These organizations are mostly left organizations, including peace movements, political action and labor committees, progressive and civil rights groups, student organizations, schools and universities, and anti-fascist groups, including the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and other Spanish solidarity groups. The series also features multiple Communist country solidarity groups, including the National Council for American-Soviet Friendship. Documentation within each file is essentially an accumulation of information relating to certain suspected front organizations. Materials in the collection generally consist of newspaper clippings relating to the front's activities; pamphlets and other materials published by the front organization; leaflets, programs, and announcements of front rallies, meetings, and functions; and membership lists of fronts, including names and addresses. Counterattack gathered any information they could to build a case and prove that they were Communist affiliated. There are some correspondence between organization and the editors of Counterattack, in response to Communist accusations.
    - Master List of Front Organizations (12-0), undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [The Associated Blind Inc., Provisional May Day Committee, United May Day Committee] (12-0), 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [The Jewish Survey, Negro Labor Victory, New Writing Foundation, Council for Pan-American Democracy, Jews of America] (12-0), 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [American Labor Party, Second Front Labor Rally, Morrisania Co-ordinating Committee, Brandon Films, Queens Food Dealers] (12-0), 1942 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [108th Precinct Department, American Soviet Medical Society, German American Labor Council, Queens Legislative Council] (12-0), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [East Side Price Committee, Workmen's Benefit Fund, Consumers Council of Elmhurst, American-Polish Labor Council] (12-0), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Contemporary Writers, China Veterans Action Committee, New Institute, New Leader, Foreign Policy Association] (12-0), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Concourse Lodge 521, Consumer and Tenants of Greenwich Village, Metropolitan Music School, World Tourists Inc.] (12-0), 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Overseas Parcels Inc., Progressive Forum, American Committee of Jewish Writers, Dreiser Workshop] (12-0), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [National Union Farmer, People's Program Service, The Forum, Student Committee for the Defense of Professor Bradley] (12-0), 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [May Day Peace Parade, Village Conference for Legislative Action, Trade Union Committee to Elect Win the War Candidates] (12-0), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [United May Day Provisional Committee, Workers Bookshop, National Youth Assembly Against Universal Military Training, NY Student Federation Against War, Town Hall, Institute of World Affairs] (12-0), 1939-1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Young People's Record Club, American Negro Theater, China Aid Council, People's Peace, American Youth for World Youth] (12-0), 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [International Programs, James M. Cain Plan, American Writers Association, Hollywood Committee of 56, Cooperative School for Teachers] (12-0), 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [New School, Conference on the German Problem, German American, Provisional May Day Committee, Award Films] (12-0), 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Friends of Widows and Orphans of the French Resistance, American-Soviet Music Society, National Committee for Negro Rights] (12-0), 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [League for Mutual Aid, Films for Progress, Stop Censorship Committee, Alcoholic Foundation, Workmen's Circle, People's Program] (12-0), 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [INTERN, WACL, "Propaganda," Church Peace Union, Hollywood Community Group] (12-0), 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [May Day Parade, United Harlem Tenants and Consumers Organization, Jewish Telegraph Agency] (12-0), 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [National Conference on American Policy in Greece, Action Conference on Indonesia, Marshall Feng Memorial Meeting, Independent Citizens Committee for the Election of Edward N. Washington] (12-0), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Universal Distributors Company, Institute for Democratic Education, Film Councils of America, Independent Theatre Owners Association, Society of the Prevention of World War III] (12-0), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Youth of All Nations, American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Radio Listeners of Northern California, American International Singers, Lower West Side District Committee] (12-0), 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Gaer Associates, Freedom Records, Farm Research, Bronx Committee Against Discrimination, Brooklyn Citizens Committee] (12-0), 1947-1949 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Americans for Polish Jews, Conference on Constitutional Liberties in America, Women's Action Committee, New Stages Daily Compass] (12-0), 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Highlander Folk School, Foster Parents' Plan for War Children, Women's International League for Peace, Survey Associates, Croatian Fraternal Union, "Steel Helmets," Help Organize Peace Everywhere, Expose] (12-0), 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Followers of the Trail, English Cultural Conference, Brooklyn Committee Against Universal Military Training, Artist Equity Association, Great Neck Peace Forum, Citizens Emergency Defense Conference, New York Jewish Conference] (12-0), 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [American National Council of America, Hollywood Anti-Nazi League, Broadway Supports the Miners, National Committee to Combat Antisemitism] (12-0), 1950-1953 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Fronts, Miscellaneous [Lists of "Communist Fronts"] (12-0), 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - United Committee for South-Slavic Americans; American Slav Congress; American Association for Reconstruction in Yugoslavia (12-1), 1944-1949 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Ambijan, American Birobidjan Committee (12-2), 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - American Committee for Armenian Rights, Armenian National Council of America (12-3), 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy (12-4), 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 49-54)
    - American Labor Party (12-5), 1939-1948 (Box 4, Folder 55-56)
    - Civil Rights Congress and Affiliates (12-7), 1938-1948 (Box 4, Folder 57-58)
    - Civil Rights Congress and Affiliates (12-7), 1938-1948 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - The Trenton Six (12-7A), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Council on African Affairs (12-9), 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Greek-American Council; American Relief for Greek Democracy; American Council for a Democratic Greece (12-10), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Progressive Citizens of America/Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences and Professions (12-11), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 6-8)
    - Indonesia League of America (12-12), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Workers Personal Service Bureau (12-13), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - National Citizens Emergency Relief Committee to Aid Strikers' Families (12-14), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (12-15), 1941-1955 (Box 5, Folder 12-15)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, Committee of Women (12-15A), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - National Negro Congress (12-16), 1941-1947 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - People's Songs/Stage for Action (12-17), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Win the Peace Conference; National Conference to Win the Peace (12-18), 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Indusco, Inc. American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Affairs (12-19), 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Russian War Relief, Inc.; American Society for Russian Relief, Inc. (12-20), 1942-1949 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - New York Committee for Justice in Freeport (12-21), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Japanese-American Committee for Democracy (12-22), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 25-26)
    - Schools [School for Democracy, School for Jewish Studies, Davis School, Schools Council of Brownsville and East New York, George Washington Carver School, School for Contemporary Writers, Camps-New York State] (12-23), 1939-1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Schools [Experimental School, Brookwood Labor College, Robert Louis Stevenson] (12-23), 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Schools [School for Democracy, Jefferson School of Social Science, School of Jewish Studies, Metropolitan Music School, George Washington Carver School, Eugene Debs School, Red Medical School, Workshop] (12-23), 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - In Fact (12-24), 1945-1951 (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
    - Trade Union Committee for Jewish Unity, American Jewish Labor Council (12-25), 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Book Find Club (12-26), 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
    - Artists' League of America; Artists Union; American Artists Congress; American Contemporary Artists (12-27), 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Spanish file [American Committee for Spanish Freedom, American Rescue Ship Mission, Action Committee to Free Spain Now, United American Spanish Aid Committee, Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee] (12-28), 1938-1951 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Spanish file [Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, American Committee for Spanish Freedom, Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee] (12-28), 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Spanish file [Spanish Refugee Appeal, Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, Spanish Information Bureau] (12-28), 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Spanish file [Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, Spanish Refugee Appeal, Action Committee to Free Spain, Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee] (12-28), 1945-1950 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - American Legion (12-30), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - The Protestant (12-31), 1943-1948 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - International Workers Order (12-32), 1940-1966 (Box 5, Folder 42-43)
    - Political Action Committee, CIO; National Citizens (12-33), 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 44-45)
    - Political Action Committee, CIO (12-33-1A), 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Fronts, Defunct [National Council of Negro Women, Committee for the Care of Young Children in Wartime, Association of Southern Women for the Prevention of Lynching, Eastside Conference to Defend America by Defeating Hitler, New York Conference for Inalienable Rights] (12-34), 1941-1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Fronts, Defunct [League for National Unity, New York Trade Union, Committee to Elect Labor's Candidates, Trade Union Committee to Keep Marcantonio in Congress, Institute for Propaganda Analysis, New Theatre League, Pioneer Youth of America, New York Peace Association] (12-34), 1940-1944 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Fronts, Defunct [Trade Union Art School, Book Union Inc., Independent Veterans Committee for the Election of Progressive Candidates, Council of US Veterans, Lawyers Committee on American Relations with Spain, Saturday Forum Luncheon Group, National Committee for People's Rights] (12-34), 1939-1946 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Fronts, Defunct [American Music League, The World Community, Propaganda Analysis] (12-34), 1937-1943 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - American Peace Mobilization; American People's Mobilization (12-35), 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
    - Veterans Against Discrimination, Affiliate of Civil Rights Congress (12-36), 1946 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - People's Institute of Applied Religion (12-38), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - American Youth for Democracy; Young Communist League (12-40), 1938-1948 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Youth; Publication of American Youth for Democracy (12-40A), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Labor Youth League (12-40B), 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Austro-American Committee (12-41), 1942 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - American Russian Institute (12-42), 1937-1949 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    - American Student Union (12-43), 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - American League for Peace and Democracy (12-44), 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - American Youth Congress (12-45), 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 22-23)
    - National Lawyers Guild (12-46), 1940-1951 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Workers' Alliance of America (12-49), 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Fronts, Publications [New Masses, Great Concord Tide, The Span, Soviet Russia Today, Reader's Scope, The People's Voice, The German American, Trends and Tides, Prompt Press, New Union Press] (12-50), 1945-1953 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Fronts, Publications [Pamphlet Press, New Masses, Asia] (12-50), 1938-1947 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Consumers' Union (12-51), 1946-1952 (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
    - Congress of American Women (12-52), 1945-1949 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Young Progressives of America (Youth for Wallace) (12-53A), 1944-1966 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Progressive Party (Third Party or Party for Wallace) (12-53), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 1-3, Box 6, Folder 33-36)
    - Progressive Party Petition Signers, Pittsburgh Area (12-53B), 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - New Council of American Business, Inc. (12-54), 1934-1947 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Conference of Progressives (12-56), 1946 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - American Council, Institute for Pacific Relations (12-57), 1945-1948 (Box 7, Folder 7-9)
    - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America (12-58), 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - People's Radio Foundation (12-59), 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - California Labor School (12-60), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - League of Women Shoppers (12-61), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Southern Conference for Human Welfare (12-62), 1944-1949 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Stop Censorship Committee (12-63), 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - United Christian Council for Democracy (12-65), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (12-66), 1937-1956 (Box 7, Folder 17-21)
    - League for Industrial Democracy (12-67), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Physicians Forum (12-68), 1946-1953 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - American Committee of Jewish Writers, Artists, and Scientists (12-69), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Committee of One Thousand (12-70), 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Committee for Democratic Rights (Provisional) (12-71), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - United World Federalists, Inc. (12-72), 1948-1950 (Box 7, Folder 27-29)
    - Yale University (12-73), 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
    - Harvard University (12-73A), undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - New York University (12-73B), 1949 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Film Audiences for Democracy (12-74), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - National Gazette (12-75), 1948 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Negro Labor Congress (12-76), 1947 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Sons of Liberty Boycott Committee (12-77), 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - American Friends of India (12-78), 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - American Veterans of the Philippine Campaign (12-79), 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Jefferson School of Social Science (12-80), 1946-1956 (Box 7, Folder 40-41)
    - Jefferson School of Social Science (12-80), 1946-1956 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Consumer and Tenant Fronts [New York City Consumers Counsel, Consumer Farmers Milk Cooperative, Northern Boulevard Houses Tenants Association, Flushing Consumers Cooperative, United Harlem Tenants and Consumers] (12-81), 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - United Committee to Save the Jewish State and the United Nations (12-82), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - World Congress of Intellectuals Affiliate: International Committee in Defense of Peace (12-83), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace, Progressive Citizens of America (12-83A), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
    - Waldorf Culture Conference Speeches (12-83A), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
    - Paris Peace Congress and the American Sponsoring Committee of the World Peace Congress (12-83B), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - American Continental Congress for Peace (12-83C), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - American Jewish Congress (12-84), 1946-1949 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Intelligence Research Bureau Reports (12-85), 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 14-24)
    - Scientists' Committee on Loyalty Problems, Loyalty Checks-General (12-86), 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - China Welfare Fund (China Welfare Appeal) (12-87), 1948-1955 (Box 8, Folder 26)